<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on roamingthings</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/categories/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on roamingthings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Alexander Sparkowsky</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:51:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roamingthings.de/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 053: June 4, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day053/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:51:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day053/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Implemented integration-tests for OAuth 2 token retrieval.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: Learned many details about the different OAuth 2 grant_types and flows. This demonstrates how much you can learn when implementing tests ;)
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Cleanup the tests and maybe implement some more API endpoints.
Link(s) to work: security-server</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 052: June 3, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day052/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 18:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day052/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: F-I-N-A-L-L-Y got OAuth 2 and session/UI based authorization with Spring Security working.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: A lot about Spring Security filters, and security configuration.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Improve the api of the server by adding some more features.
Link(s) to work: security-server</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 051: June 3, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day051/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 20:17:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day051/</guid><description>By looking deeper into the inner mechanics of Spring Security and OAuth2 I started to get an idea where my problem arises.
Basically I&amp;rsquo;m trying to combine a REST resource secured by an OAuth 2 generated token (implicit grant type) and a &amp;ldquo;general&amp;rdquo; web page protected by a login form and session based authentication mechanism.
It seems as if all filters that are needed for the different authentication methods require a very special filter combination.</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 050: June 1, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day050/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 18:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day050/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Another day struggling with OAuth 2 and Spring.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: Nothing new.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: I will start over tomorrow.
Link(s) to work: Nothing to show</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 049: May 31, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day049/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 18:20:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day049/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Improved security configuration but still not where I want to be.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: Spring Security (again). I&amp;rsquo;m sure there is just one tiny pice missing.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Continue working on the authentication.
Link(s) to work: security-server</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 048: May 30, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day048/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 19:47:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day048/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Continued on getting a form based login in the authorization server to work. Obviously I didn&amp;rsquo;t yet quiet understand the form based login mechanism in Spring. So I will concentrate on that tomorrow.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: Nothing final yet
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Invest more time in looking at the form based login mechanism in Spring Security.
Link(s) to work: No visible work for today</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 047: May 29, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day047/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:10:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day047/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Continued separating the authentication and user management services from each other.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: Setting up a Spring Boot project became quite fast for me ;)
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Implement a simple login form for the auth server.
Link(s) to work: security-server</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 046: May 28, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day046/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 16:41:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day046/</guid><description>Security Server While I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering around with Spring Security and all the nice things it offers I became very interested in this domain. Also I know there are a lot of good ready-to-use servers and services out there I wanted to have a field to experiment with the thing that Spring offers.
I decided to start this project as an independent server which offers SSO authorization and user management for the other services and clients I plan to build.</description></item></channel></rss>