<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>I2C on roamingthings</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/tags/i2c/</link><description>Recent content in I2C on roamingthings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 Alexander Sparkowsky</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 13:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roamingthings.de/tags/i2c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 065: June 24, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day065/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day065/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t published my progress in the last few days also I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on my Project. This is due to the fact that I have been working on getting I2C working on my STM32 and just didn&amp;rsquo;t get it. Today I started a last try and finally was able to talk to let my STM32 talk to my BME280 environment sensor. I will post my findings in a separate post.</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 064: June 20, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day064/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 18:10:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day064/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Setup the project on a new board and rewired everything. This allows me to move the project around more easily. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been looking into more I2C code.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the interior of a breadboard :) Finally&amp;hellip;
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Continue on I2C code.
Link(s) to work:</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 063: June 19, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day063/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:33:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day063/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Started to write I2C code. Unfortunately it&amp;rsquo;s not running yet. Although the examples are working well, using these for an own project is not that easy.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned: How to configure I2C on an STM32. Specially when it comes to more modern STM32 like the L4 family some things are different compared to the more mature families like the F1 or F4.
Things I&amp;rsquo;ve planned for tomorrow: Continue with I2C code.</description></item><item><title>[100 Days of Code] Day 062: June 18, 2017</title><link>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day062/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roamingthings.de/posts/100doc-day062/</guid><description>After struggling with the security server integration tests the last days (or weeks?) and being sick for the last days I decided to continue on my second project wich aims at reading and processing environmental data with a STM32 MCU. Today I setup the circuit and got into the Digilent Analog Discovery 2.
Today&amp;rsquo;s Progress: Setting up the circuit and testing an I2C display with an Arduino which I will use as a Hello World tool.</description></item></channel></rss>